Nick Leslie

Software Engineer and Engineering People Leader

🕲 Washington, District of Columbia, United States, 20009 ၆ 202 400 1892 @ ncpleslie@gmail.com & https://nickleslie.dev

in nicholas-leslie 🕥 ncpleslie

Summary

I am a **Full-Stack Software Engineer** and an **Engineering People Leader** with expertise in web development, automation, and cloud services. I have a track record of always exploring new technologies and delivering outstanding applications for my clients.

Experience

Engineering People Leader | September 2022 - August 2023

Jade Software Corporation

- Supported a team of Software Engineers by providing leadership, mentorship, communication, and training. Through regular one-on-ones, structured training sessions and code reviews
- Participated in software development projects, from pre-sales, design, development and delivery. Engaging with clients throughout the software development lifecycle
- Provided technical expertise and guidance across the company, supporting innovation and improvement as the go-to domain expert on numerous technologies and projects

Software Engineer | July 2020 - September 2022

Jade Software Corporation

- Contributed to an agile, multi-functional team, using the Scrum methodology to develop cloud-native web applications for global clients
- Collaborated across the software development lifecycle, managing requirements, API design, implementation, testing, code reviews, and deployment
- Maintained client satisfaction through proactive engagement, gathering requirements, and delivering regular progress updates to clients and stakeholders

Computer Vision Intern | December 2019 - February 2020

Jade Software Corporation

• Developed a computer vision application for running on the Edge to enhance the capabilities of security cameras. Allowing them to perform license plate recognition, object tracking and detection. Using **Python**, **OpenCV**, and **OpenVino**

Projects

Air New Zealand Crew Claims Portal

Led a team to develop a secure web portal for submitting expense claims for pilots and crew members. Using **TypeScript, Vue 3, Tailwind, Vitest, NodeJS, GitHub, GitHub Actions** and deployed to **Azure** with **Azure Active Directory, API-M,** and **Static Web Apps**

Skipton Document Management System

Part of a team that developed a document storage system for the regulated financial sector. Manages 180M+ documents, ingesting millions monthly. Developed with **TypeScript**, **Vue 3**, **Tailwind**, **C#**, .**Net**, **EF Core**, **xUnit**. Deployed on **Azure** with **CosmosDB** and **Blob Storage**

A https://www.jadeworld.com/services/jade-digital/our-clients/skipton-case-study

DB Cargo Employee Hub

Full-stack developer in a team that developed a secure **Android** application for a DB Cargo UK to access training resources, documentation, schedules, etc. Domain and API designed with **UML**. Using **C#**, **Xamarin**, **EF Core**, **Domain-Driven Design**, .**NET**, **SQLite**, and **MSSQL**

 ${\boldsymbol{\mathcal{O}}}\ \ \text{https://www.jadeworld.com/services/jade-digital/our-clients/db-cargo-uk-case-study}$

Zurich Insurance Calculator

Developed a white-labeled, configuration-driven insurance (Life, TPD) calculator for Zurich Insurance, Australia. Using **Angular** for front-end and **.NET** for the back-end. Deployed to **Azure** with **App Service** and **CosmosDB**

https://zurich.zurichcalculators.net/

WMATA Train Tracker

Personally developed a WMATA train tracking application is for monitoring the metro train arrival times in the DMV area. Built with **Go**, **Wails**, **SOLC**, **SOLite**, **TypeScript**, **Vue 3**, **Tailwind**, **Nuxt 3**, **tRPC**, **Zod**, and **GitHub Actions**

A https://github.com/ncpleslie/wmata-train-tracker

Draw For Them

Personally developed an ephemeral image sharing and drawing application. Built with NextJS, TypeScript, React, Jest, FabricJS, tRPC, NextAuth, WebSockets, Postgres, and Prisma

https://github.com/ncpleslie/draw-for-them

Education

Ara Institute of Canterbury
Major in Software Engineering
First Class with Distinction

Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology November 2020